Chapter 113.
the forge.
with matted beard and suathed in a bristling sharkskin apron. About midday,
Perth was standing between his forge and anvil, the ladder placed upon an
ironwood log, with one hand holding a pike head in the coals, and with the
other at his forge's lungs, when Captain Ahab came along, carrying in his hand a
small, rusty looking leather bag, while yet a little distance from the forge
Moody Ahab paused, till at last Perth, withdrawing his iron from the fire,
began hammering it upon the anvil. The red mass sending off the sparks in thick
hovering flights, some of which flew close to Ahab.
Are these thy mother carries chickens, Perth? They are always flying in thy
wake. Birds of good omen, too, but not to all. Look here, they burn. But thou,
thou livest among them without a scorch.
Because I am scorched all over, Captain Ahab, answered Perth, resting for a
moment on his hammer. I am past scorching. Not easily cance thou scorch a scar.
Well, well, no more. Thy shrunk voice sounds too calmly, sainely woeful to me.
In no paradise myself, I am impatient of all misery and others that is not mad.
Thou shouldst go mad, blacksmith, say, Why dust thou not go mad? How canst thou
endure without being mad? Do the heavens yet hate thee that thou canst not go
mad? What thou making there?
Welding an old pike head, sir, there were seams and dents in it. And thou
make it all smooth again, blacksmith, after such hard usage as it had? I think so, sir.
And I suppose thou can smooth almost any seams and dents, never mind how hard the
metal blacksmith.
I sir, I think I can. All seams and dents but one.
Look you here then, cried Ahab, passionately advancing and leaning with
both hands on Perth's shoulders. Look you here. Here. Can you smooth out a
seam like this, blacksmith? sweeping one hand across his ribbed brow. If thou
couldst blacksmith, glad enough would I lay my head upon thy anvil and feel thy
heaviest hammer between my eyes. Answer, cast thou smooth this seam.
Oh, that is the one, sir, said I, not all seams and dense but one. I,
blacksmith, it is the one, I, man. It is unsoable.
For though thou only cease it here in my flesh, it is worked down into the bone
of my skull. That is all wrinkles. But away with child's play. No more gaffs
and pikes today. Look you here, jingling the leather bag as if it were full of gold coins.
I too want a harpoon made, one that a thousand yolk of fiends could not part
Perth. Something that will stick in a whale like his own fin bone. There's the
stuff. Flinging the pouch upon the anvil. Look ye blacksmith. These are the
gathered nail stubs of the steel shoes of racing horses. Horseshoe stubs, sir.
Why, Captain Ahab? Thou hast there then the best and stubbornest stuff we blacksmiths ever work.
I know it, old man.
These stubs will weld together like glue from the melted bones of murderers.
Quick, forge me the harpoon, and forge me first 12 rods for its shank. Then
wind and twist and hammer these 12 together like the yarns and strands of a
tow line. Quick, I'll blow the fire.
When at last the 12 rods were made, Ahab tried them one by one by spiraling them
with his own hand round a long, heavy iron bolt. A flaw, rejecting the last
one. Work that over again, Perth. This done, Perth was about to begin welding
the 12 into one, when Ahab stayed his hand and said he would weld his own
iron. as then, with regular gasping hems, he hammered on the anvil, Perth
passing to him the glowing rods, one after the other, and the hardpressed
forge shooting up its intense straight flame. The Parsy passed silently, and
bowing over his head towards the fire, seemed invoking some curse or some
blessing on the toil. But as Ahab looked up, he slid aside.
What's that bunch of Lucifers dodging about, therefore, muttered Stub, looking
on from the folks. That parsy smells fire like a fusy, and smells of it
himself like a hot musket's powder pan.
At last the shank, in one complete rod received its final heat, and as Perth,
to temper it, plunged it all hissing into the cask of water nearby, the
scalding steam shot up into Ahab's bent face. W thou brand me, Perth? Wincing
for a moment with the pain. Have I been but forging my own branding iron? Then
pray God not that. Yet I fear something, Captain Ahab. Is not this harpoon for
the white whale? Or the white fiend?
But now for the barbs. Thou must make them thyself, man. Here are my razors,
the best of steel. here and make the barb sharp as the needle sleet of the icy sea.
For a moment the old blacksmith eyed the razors as though he would fain not use
them. Take them, man. I have no need for them, for I now neither shave, suck, nor
prey till.
But here to work. Fashioned at last into an arrowy shape and welded by Perth to
the shank, the steel soon pointed the end of the iron, and as the blacksmith
was about giving the barbs their final heat prior to tempering them, he cried
to Ahab to place the water cask near.
No, no, no water for that. I wanted of the true death temper. Ahoy there,
Tashego Quiqu Doo. What say you pagans?
Will you give me as much blood as will cover this barb? Holding it high up. A
cluster of dark nods replied, "Yes."
Three punctures were made in the heathen flesh, and the white whale's barbs were
then tempered. "Ago, nonbaptiso enomi,"
deliriously howled Ahab as the malignant iron scorchingly devoured the baptismal blood.
Now mustering the spare poles from below and selecting one of hickory with the
bark still investing it, Ahab fitted the end to the socket of the iron. A coil of
new towine was then unwound and some fathoms of it taken to the windless and
stretched to a great tension. Pressing his foot upon it till the rope hummed
like a harpstring. Then eagerly bending over it and seeing no strandings, Ahab
exclaimed, "Good." And now for the seizings.
At one extremity the rope was unstranded, and the separate spread
yarns were all braided and woven round the socket of the harpoon. The pole was
then driven hard up into the socket.
From the lower end, the rope was traced halfway along the pole's length and
firmly secured so with interwistings of twine. This done, pole, iron, and rope
like the three fates remained inseparable. And Ahab moodily stalked
away with the weapon, the sound of his ivory leg, and the sound of the hickory
pole both hollowy ringing along every plank. But air he entered his cabin,
light, unnatural, half bantering, yet most pitious sound was heard. Oh, Pip,
thy wretched laugh, thy idle but unresting eye, all thy strange mummies
not unmeaningly blended with the black tragedy of the melancholy ship, and mocked it.